### Dhruv Jawalkar

2nd Year Student, M.S in Computer Science at Oregon State University

Specializing in Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Software Engineering

Graduate Teaching Assistant,

Blog: https://dopelemon.me

Github: https://github.com/DhruvJawalkar

Linkedln: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhruv-jawalkar-43b8816b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhruv-jawalkar-43b8816b/</a>

Mobile: (510) 399-3469

Email: dhruv.jawalkar@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

2 years of experience in building Computer Vision, Deep Learning related projects; reading and implementing latest research papers in the field into innovative product ideas. Prior to this I have 4 years of product development experience as a Senior Software Engineer including experience at a silicon valley Ad-Tech startup.

Programming languages: Python, JavaScript, Bash, HTML, CSS

ML Stack: PyTorch, TensorFlow, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow.js, Jupyter

Notebook, OpenCV, Flask, Matlab

Web Technologies: React, Angular, Grunt, Gulp, NGINX

Software and tools: Git, Visual Studio, WebStorm

#### **PROJECTS**

Pose Estimation: Realtime User Activity Guidance on a CPU

PyTorch, OpenCV, Python

Developed novel application which performs realtime human pose estimation via webcam feed and provides activity guidance via relative angles between limbs

### **Crop Growth Monitoring: Hydroponic Farming**

OpenCV, Python, Scikit-Learn

Developed novel application which tracks crop growth via webcam feed, models inputs like nutrients in solution, humidity, temperature, light duration to understand and improve crop maturity and time to market

Paper Implementation : Depth Prediction from Single Image using Multi-Scale Deep Network

PyTorch, Python, Jupyter Notebook

Developed and open sourced the implementation of the paper on Depth Prediction

## Paper Implementation : OpenPose - Realtime Multi-Person 2D Pose Estimation using Part Affinity Fields

PyTorch, Python, Jupyter Notebook

Developed from scratch and open sourced the implementation of the paper on Human Pose Estimation, Implementation can be found on my Github account

# Computer Vision and Deep Learning Blog : Articles explaining latest research papers in the field

Flask, Python, NGINX, React, HTML/CSS

Topics include Semantic Segmentation, Depth Prediction, GAN's, Object Detection, Pose Estimation https://dopelemon.me

### **EXPERIENCE**

Kony Labs, India - Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2016 - Jun 2017

 Part of MBaaS (Mobile Backend as a Service) console team, was hired and responsible for improving console performance and user experience.

### **Engage BDR, India** - Software Engineer

April 2016 - Dec 2016

• Lead front-end development for upcoming product ICONICREACH, platform to connect brand advertisers to Instagram celebrity influencers.

### Fission Labs, India - Ul Engineer

Aug 2013 - April 2016

- Built web apps for silicon valley Ad-Tech startup, DeepForestMedia
- Developed their online Ad campaign management portal, DSP.
- Developed campaign performance monitoring dashboard, which helped customers make effective business decisions.

### **EDUCATION**

**Oregon State University, USA** - M.S in Computer Science (Software Innovation Track)

Sept 2018 - Current (GPA: 3.7)

BITS-Pilani, India - B.E Hons. in Computer Science

Aug 2009 - July 2013